[MUSIC]
[음악]
Now we've seen classification in a wide variety of settings and how we can really
여러 환경에서 분류와 데이터를 통해
use to predict a class like a positive or negative sentiment from data.
긍정,부정 감성 클래스 예측에 이용하는 법을 배웠습니다
In the regression section, Amy talked about this block diagram that
회귀 부분에서 에밀리가 이 블록 다이어그램으로
really describes how a machine learning algorithm iterates through its data.
기계학습 알고리즘이 어떻게 데이터를 반복 적용 되는지 설명했습니다
So now let’s take this same block diagram and work through it and
분류 중 감성 분석의 영역에서
describe how it works out in the case of classification with sentiment analysis.
알고리즘이 어떻게 작동하는지 알아볼 시간입니다
So how does it look for classification for
감성 분석을 위한 분류를
sentiment, so in this case,
어떻게 하냐하면 이 경우
the data is the text of the reviews, so
데이터가 리뷰 텍스트이니 각 리뷰에 대해
for each review, the text of review is
리뷰 텍스트와 그와 연관된
associated with a particular labeled sentiment
특정 라벨이 붙은 감성으로 학습합니다
From that text of the review, we feed it to through a feature
리뷰 텍스트를 특징 추출 단계에 집어넣으면
extraction phase which gives us x, the inputs to our algorithm.
x가 나오는데 이게 알고리즘의 입력이 됩니다
And this x here is going to be the word counts.
x는 단어수입니다
So word counts for every data point, for every review.
모든 데이터 점, 모든 리뷰의 단어를 셉니다
Now our Machine Learning model is going to take that input data.
기계학습 모델은 입력 데이터를 받습니다
And so the word counts, as well as some several parameters
단어수와 각 단어의 가중치인 w^과 같은
which I'm calling here w-hat, which are the weights for each word.
파라미터입니다
Each word.
각 단어
And from, combining these two, we're gonna output the predictions.
이 둘을 합쳐서 예측을 만들어 냅니다
So if the score is greater than zero, it's gonna be positive.
점수가 0보다 크면 긍정입니다
If the score is less than zero, it's gonna be negative.
점수가 0보다 작으면 부정입니다
So this output here is the predicted sentiment.
결과값은 예측된 감성입니다
And if we're just using the model, we would be done here.
모델을 사용만 한다면 이것으로 끝입니다
But really, in the machine learning algorithm phase, we're gonna evaluate that
하지만 기계학습 알고리즘 단계에서 결과를 평가하고
result and then feed it back into the algorithm to improve the parameters.
알고리즘에 되먹여서 파라미터를 향상시킵니다
So we're gonna take the predicted sentiment, y-hat and
예측된 감성 y^을
compare it with the true label for the sentiment.
그 감성의 참 라벨과 비교합니다
So the sentiment label for each data point.
모든 데이터 점에 대한 감성 라벨입니다
So that's gonna fit in and
그렇게 들어가면
our quality measure here is gonna be classification accuracy.
품질 기준이 분류 정확도가 됩니다
Classification accuracy.
분류 정확도
And the machine learning algorithm, which we're gonna discuss in more detail
분류 강의에서 자세히 다룰 기계학습 알고리즘은
in the classification course, is gonna take that accuracy and try to improve it.
정확도를 더 향상시키려고 할 겁니다
And the way the improvement works, is by updating the parameter w-hat.
방법은 파라미터 w^을 갱신하는 것입니다
And that's what the cycle for
기계학습 알고리즘 분류 작업 사이클을
machine learning algorithm classification would look like.
알아봤습니다
In this module, we've seen how to do classification.
이 모듈에서 분류 하는 법을 알아봤습니다
We've looked at various examples of where it can be applied.
분류가 적용될 수 있는 여러 예제를 살펴봤습니다
We'll talked about a few models for building classifications,
분류 모델을 몇 개 알아볼텐데
especially in the context of sentiment analysis, we saw some live demos.
라이브 데모로 본 감성분석이 주가 됩니다
And we even built a notebook where we built a classifier from data and
노트북에서 데이터를 통해 분류기를 만들고
analyzed it.
분석합니다
And with this knowledge, you're ready to build an intelligent application
이 지식이면 분류기를 핵심으로 하는
that uses a classifier at its core.
지능형 애플리케이션을 만들 준비를 마치게 됩니다
[MUSIC]
[음악]